ppa
っ走
shi
tte
って
ku
く
ze
ぜ
GLORY
DAYS!
What... happened then?
（向(こう)）
それから どうなったのですか？
I was put on Xia's carriage.
（政(せい)）
俺は紫夏(しか)たちの馬車に乗せられた
だが その前後のことは
よく覚えていない
Though I don't remember what happened in the events surrounding that.
夢を…
（向）えっ？
A dream...
Because I was having a bad dream.
（政）悪い夢を見ていたからな
Who exactly... is going to be king?
（幻影）誰が王になるって？
アア…
Who is going to be king?
Who?
（幻影）誰が…
ウワッ！
Are you awake?
（紫夏）お目覚めですか？
（政）ハッ…
お前は…
You're...
（政）ウワーッ！
Zheng and Zi Xia
What's wrong?!
（道剣(どうけん)）どうされました？
Please! Please calm down!
どうか…
どうか落ち着いてくだされ！
I expected you to be surprised when you woke up and you were on a carriage.
目覚めてみれば馬車の上
驚かれたとは思いますが 事情を…
So please, let me... let me explain the situation to you!
今 事情をお話ししますゆえ
落ち着いてくだされ！
Please, calm yourself!
And that is our situation.
（道剣）…という次第です
We are planning for your mother
to escape using a different path.
母君は
別の道で脱出を図っております
Do not worry.
ご心配なく
咸陽(かんよう)で必ず再会できます
You will surely reunite in Xiangyang.
It'll still be some time before we reach the gate.
（紫夏）
関まで あとしばらくあります
もう少しお休みいただいて
結構ですよ
It's okay to rest a little longer.
うむ…
I suppose we are to continue straight to the gate?
やはり このまま関に進むのか？
（紫夏）それが いちばんです
That is the best way.
We'll use our usual road to not draw suspicion.
怪しまれぬよう
いつもの道を使います
There are five gates on this road before we escape the State of Zhao.
この道で趙国(ちょうこく)を脱するまで
通過する関門は５つ
If we can make it through them,
we can reach the State of Qin.
（紫夏）
それさえ抜ければ 秦国(しんこく)へ行けます
５つか…
Five, eh?
I-I came prepared for this,
（田慈(でんじ)）か… 覚悟はしていたが
but do we have any way to fool the investigators there?
取り調べの役人を
ごまかす手だてはあるんだろうな？
（江彰(こうしょう)）
うるせえな… そういうことは
こっちに任せとけよ
Pipe down. You just leave that stuff to us.
If we get through five, we make it to Qin?
５つ くぐれば 秦国か
（紫夏）ご心配は無用ですよ
No need to worry.
I, Zi Xia, will definitely deliver you
safely to the State of Qin.
この紫夏が 必ず
無事に秦国までお届けいたします
Is this reality?
これは現実か？
（紫夏）もちろん現実ですよ
Of course it's reality.
The 1st Barrier
—Huian—
Okay, let's go!
よし 行くぞ！
空(から)の俵があります
政さまは その中に
There is an empty straw sack.
Place Lord Zheng inside it.
I will drive the carriage.
馬車の御者は 私がやりましょう
Next! Could you hurry it up?!
（役人Ａ）
次！ 早くせんか！ ほら 次！
C'mon, next!
What is this cargo?
（役人Ａ）何じゃ？ この荷は
金貨ではないか　捕らえよ！
Ain't these gold coins?
Arrest him!
No, you have it wrong!
（商人）えっ？ いや 違うんです！
やめてください！
P-Please, stop!
Okay, next!
（役人Ａ）よし 次！
Thanks, as always!
毎度！
（役人Ａ）おう 通せ！
Yes! Let them through!
Okay, next!
（役人Ａ）よし 次！
W-What was that just now?!
な… 何だ？ 今のは
あれだけで通れるのか？
They let us through just because you said that?!
It's because we're black marketeers that carry illegal goods.
違法な物を運ぶ闇商人ですからねえ
常日ごろから
手回しを怠ってはいませんよ
Normally, you have to be vigilant about your preparations.
（道剣たち）ハァ…
（亜門(あもん)）勘違いすんなよ
Don't get the wrong idea.
Not all black marketeers can just slip through like that.
（亜門）闇商人全員が
すり抜けられるわけじゃねえぞ
But this is Zi Xia we're talking about here.
紫夏だから できるんだ
Ever since she took over as the leader,
（亜門）なんつったって
こいつは 家督を継いでから―
our business has doubled in size.
商いを
倍の規模に膨らませたんだからな
オホホホッ… 商才 商才
I've just have a talent for business.
I had questioned why Lü Buwei would recommend such young people,
なぜ こんな若者たちを
呂不韋(りょふい)が推薦してきたのか
疑問に思っていたが
今 理由が分かった
but now I see why.
Looking at him closely like this,
his body is covered in bruises.
こうして よく見ると
全身 アザだらけだ
It probably happens every day...
きっと毎日のように…
（政）ハァハァ…
（紫夏）政さま？
Lord Zheng?
（亡霊たち）苦しい… 苦しい…
苦しい… 苦しい…
It hurts...
苦しい… 苦しい… 苦しい…
（亡霊たち）苦しい… 苦しい…
（亡霊）行くな… 行かさんぞ 政
Don't go...
You must not go...
Zheng...
地の底へ お前も…
苦しい… 行かすものか
You too...
To the abyss...
It hurts...
Like hell you'll go...
The abyss...
地の底へ… 地の底へ… 地の底へ…
（政）
黙れ！ 長平は俺には関係ない
俺は秦国へ帰る！
Shut up!
Changping had nothing to do with me!
I'm going back to the State of Qin!
What will you do in the State of Qin?
（幻影）何をする？ 秦国に？
誰が… 誰が… する？
Who?
Do?
Go?
帰る？ 秦国へ帰って何を？
What're ya gonna go to the State of Qin for?
You've gotta be kidding.
冗談だろう？
Because... you're no longer...
何せ お前は もう…
ウワーッ！
What's wrong?!
（道剣）どうした？
（亜門）またか
Again?!
政さま！
（政）ハァハァ…
Lord Zheng!
Lord Zheng seems to be in an odd condition.
（道剣）
“政さまの様子がおかしい”？
Everyone has nightmares.
夢にうなされることなど
誰にでもある
With such a sudden change in his life, it makes sense for him to be a bit shaken.
（道剣）状況が急転して
まだ少し混乱しておられるのだろう
But...
しかし…
（道剣）それに 今は とにかく―
At any rate, what we have to do now is escape Zhao.
まず趙を脱出すること
これだけですぞ 紫夏どの
That is all, Miss Zi Xia.
The 2nd Barrier
—Qingguo—
There's the gate.
（道剣）関です　政さま 俵の中へ
Put Lord Zheng in the sack.
So the top priority is to escape Zhao?
“趙を脱出することが第一”か
確かに そうだが…
He has a point, but...
（兵士）フフッ…
（兵士）おお いいな
That's a nice one.
Oh, if it isn't Zi Xia?!
（茂英(もえい)）おお 紫夏じゃ 紫夏じゃ！
久しぶりだな
It's been such a long time!
You seem to be doing well, Mr. Mao Ying.
お元気そうで 茂英どの
I haven't seen you at all recently.
最近 てんで現れぬが
まさか わしを
避けておるのではあるまいな？
Don't tell me you've been avoiding me?
I would never do such a thing.
まさか そのような…
フフフッ… 少し休んでいかぬか？
茶でも出そう
Would you mind taking a short break here?
I could pour you some tea.
I'm sorry, but I'm actually in a bit of a hurry.
（紫夏）
せっかくですが 先を急ぎますゆえ
Why don't you ever spend time with me?!
ならん！
たまには わしに つきあえ！
さもなくば 荷あらための命令を
出して 無理やり休ませるぞ！
If you don't, I'll call for a search of your cargo and force you to take a rest here!
（紫夏）それは困りましたなぁ
Well, I certainly don't want that...
But right now, I'm keeping customers waiting.
しかし
今は客を待たせてありますので
茶は 次に必ず…
So I'll make sure to have tea with you next ti...
Hey!
（紫夏）おい！
（兵士）えっ？
What the hell are you doing?!
（茂英）何をやってんだ お前！
（兵士）何って 試し射(う)ちを…
Just a test shot.
昨日 弓を買ったので
米俵くらい いいかと…
I just bought this bow yesterday, so I figured no one would mind me shooting a sack of rice...
Like hell I'd believe that, you bastard!
（紫夏）ふざけるな 貴様！
Don't get angry, Zi Xia!
怒るな 紫夏…
こやつは先日 入ったばかりなのだ
This fellow just started work here a few days ago.
Y-You can go now!
（茂英）もう行っていいぞ
（紫夏）フゥ…
あっ 血が…
Blood!
All the way from the gate, not only did he not yell, he hasn't made a sound.
関から ここまで 悲鳴どころか
うめき声も聞こえてこない
Is he unconscious? Or maybe...
（紫夏）気絶… もしくは…
Lord Zheng!
政さま！
Take out the arrow.
矢を抜け　出られぬ
I'm stuck.
政さま　よくぞ ご無事で
Lord Zheng... I'm so glad you're all right!
よくぞ
ひと声も発せず 我慢なされました
That was incredible how you endured that without yelling out even once!
Hold on a second...
ちょっと待て… 腕を射られて
泣かない子供が どこにいる？
Who ever heard of a child that doesn't cry when his arm gets shot with an arrow?
H-Here I go!
（単元(たんげん)）い… いきますぞ ンッ…
Who ever heard of a human who didn't twitch when an arrow was taken out of their arm?
（紫夏）
うがたれた腕から 矢を抜かれ―
眉ひとつ動かさぬ人間が
どこにいる？
What in the world is this boy?
この子は 一体…
Sometimes from having painful childhoods, people can get emotionally depressed.
幼少期のつらい経験で 感情が
ふさぎ込んでしまうことはある
War orphans like us were the same way, until our adoptive father took us in.
戦争孤児の私たちも 父に
拾われるまでは 実際そうだった
But to not even move after being shot with an arrow...
だが 矢を射られても
動じないというのは―
This goes beyond emotional trauma.
もはや 感情うんぬんの話ではない
明らかに常軌を逸している
This is clearly something abnormal.
Something is happening to this child's body and mind.
この子の心と体に何かが起きている
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
紫夏たちが邯鄲(かんたん)を出て４日
Ya Men
Jiang Zhang
一行は ついに第５の
そして 最後の関門 呂干(ろかん)に迫った
Qin
Zhao
Wei
Xiangyang
Handan
Lügan
Four days have passed since Zi Xia and the others left Handan.
The group is now finally approaching the fifth and final barrier, Lügan.
呂干を抜ければ 趙国と秦国の
国境までは 半日の距離である
If they make it through Lügan, they will be half a day's travel from the border between the states of Qin and Zhao.
How are you feeling?
（紫夏）どうされましたか？
The moon came out again.
また月が出ている
It did.
そうですね
I really like your eyes when you
look at the moon, Lord Zheng.
（紫夏）
月を見る政さまの目が
紫夏は 好きですよ
（政）時々 夢と現実の
境が分からなくなる
Sometimes I lose track of the line
between dreams and reality.
That must be hard to deal with.
それは困りました
Well, remember that whenever I'm here, it's reality.
では 私がいるときが現実と
覚えておいてください
Zi Xia...
（政）紫夏…
Can I really get to the State of Qin?
俺は本当に秦国へ帰れるのか？
I told you before.
前にも言いましたよ
私が必ず帰します
I'll make sure you get there.
The Final Barrier
—Lügan—
Okay, go on through!
（役人Ｃ）よし 通れ！
Just a minute!
（役人Ｂ）ちょっと待て！
What do you think you're doing, Zi Xia?
（役人Ｂ）
どういうことじゃ？ 紫夏
Half of the people with you are unfamiliar.
（役人Ｂ）半数も
見知らぬ顔がおるぞ
何者じゃ？ そいつらは
Who are these guys?
I've been pretty shorthanded.
人手不足でねえ
途中の村で雇ったのさ
I hired these guys in a village on my way here.
Despite their age, they're all pretty useless.
しっかし 年食ってるくせに
全然 使えなくてね
I really hope they don't end up hurting us more than helping.
（紫夏）逆に 足引っ張られて
困ってんだけど
Maybe I should leave you guys here and you can hitch a ride on a carriage going the other way?
ここに置いてくから―
入りの車が来たら
乗せてやってくんないかな？
（役人Ｂ）ハァ…
（役人Ｂ）ああ 分かった分かった
ジャマくさい　行け！
Okay, okay!
You're such a bother, just go!
フゥ…
（田慈）危なかった 危なかった！
That was close! So close!
のろしだ！
緊急閉鎖ののろしが上がっておる！
A signal fire!
An emergency closure signal fire has been raised!
閉門！ 閉門だ！
Close the gate! Close the gate!
（田慈）あっ！ 門が閉まったぞ！
They just shut the gate!
政さまのことがバレたのか？
（道剣）か… 間一髪だった
Did they learn about Lord Zheng?!
W-We made it by a hair's breadth...
ハハハッ…
やったぞ！ だが 間に合った
We did it!
We still made it in time!
We got through all of the gates!
全ての関を越えた！
これで秦国に帰れる！
Now we can make it back to the State of Qin!
（江彰）喜んでる場合じゃねえ！
（田慈）えっ？
This isn't time to celebrate!
If they did find out about Zheng, then pursuers will be coming soon!
もし政の件が知れたんなら
すぐに追っ手が来るぞ
軍が総出でな
They'll send the whole army.
He's right!
そのとおりだ
ここからは偽装の必要はない
There's no more need for disguises.
Just dump the cargo somewhere and we'll head to the state border at full speed!
（紫夏）適当な所で荷を捨て
全速で国境を目指す
The State of Zhao's mounted units are fast!
趙国の騎馬隊は速いぞ
Just a little further and we'll reach the rendezvous point!
（道剣）もう少しで合流地です！
既に迎えの軍は待機しているはず
The army should already be on standby to meet us.
There's no sign of any pursuers nearby.
（道剣）近くに追っ手の気配もない
逃げきれます！
We're going to make it!
You really saved us, Miss Zi Xia.
紫夏どのには本当に救われた
我々だけでは―
If we did this alone, it wouldn't have gone nearly as well.
こうは うまくいかなかった
感謝する！
You have our thanks!
Saved?
（紫夏）“救われた”か
Did I really save this boy?
私は本当に この子を救ったのか？
フゥ…
Looks like you're finally going home, Lord Zheng.
いよいよ ご帰国ですね 政さま
いいなぁ
帰って のちのち王になられたら
It sounds nice!
You'll go home and in the distant future, when you become king, you'll be living the life of luxury!
もう贅沢三昧(ぜいたくざんまい)ですよ
If I were only ten years younger, I could be your wife and we could live in luxury together...
私が あと10歳若かったら
妻になって 一緒に 贅沢に…
あっ “妻”は言い過ぎですね
Maybe, wife is going too far.
Maybe a concubine.
側室かな　ひょっとして召し使い？
な～んて… フフッ…
Or maybe a servant?
Just kidding.
Lord Zheng, are you all right?
（紫夏）政さま 大丈夫ですか？
政さま？ 政さま？
Lord Zheng? Lord Zheng?
Wait.
（幻影）待てよ
（政）ハッ…
Hold on... a minute...
（幻影）ちょっと待てよ
Zheng... Zheng...
政… 政…
Who is going to be king?
（幻影）誰が王になるって？
誰が王だって？
Who'd she say is king?
Who?
（幻影）誰が…
Zheng... Zheng... Zheng...
政… 政… 政…
You're going to Qin to become king?
（幻影）秦国へ帰って 王になる？
What kind of dream is that?
なに夢みてるんだ？ フフッ…
Stop this farce and get off the carriage.
こんな茶番は やめて 馬車を降りろ
お前は秦国へは行けぬ
You cannot go to the State of Qin.
Shut up!
黙れ！
（紫夏）政さま！
Lord Zheng!
どうされました？ 政さま
What's wrong, Lord Zheng?!
Who in the world would be happy if you went there?
（幻影）
お前が帰って 一体 誰が喜ぶのだ？
Who? Your father? You must be joking.
誰が？ 父君か？ 冗談だろう
父は ７年前に
お前を捨てて 秦国に帰った
Your father abandoned you to
return to Qin seven years ago.
Your mother doesn't care about you either.
母君にも お前は疎まれていた
お前さえいなければ
趙国の女に戻れたのに
If it weren't for you, she could have gone back to being a normal Zhao woman.
If it weren't for you...
お前さえいなければ
Stop! Stop! Stop!
やめろ！
（紫夏）政さま！
Lord Zheng!
What's wrong, Lord Zheng?!
どうされました？ 政さま
フフフッ…
父に捨てられ 母に疎まれた
Abandoned by your father and
neglected by your mother...
今更 戻ってこられても迷惑だよ
Even if you go home now, you'll only be a burden.
お前の場所は 秦国にはない
There is no place for you in the State of Qin.
And the biggest problem is you.
そして いちばんの問題はお前だ
お前の その心と体
That heart and body of yours...
（幻影）フフッ… まともな人間が
矢で射られて平気なはずはない
No normal human would be fine
after being shot with an arrow.
まともな人間なら！
No decent human.
You're pretty clever, so you
should have realized it long ago.
賢いお前は
もう とっくに悟っているだろう
お前みたいなヤツは
王になってはならないと
Someone like you should never become king!
Now then, how long do you intend to stay on this carriage?
さあ いつまで馬車に
いるつもりだ？ さっさと降りろ！
Hurry and get off!
（政）ウワーッ！
Zheng fell off!
（江彰）政が落ちたぞ！
（田慈）なに？
（道剣）止めろ！
What?!
Stop!
I'll go!
私が行く！ 皆は その場で待て！
（亜門）紫夏！
All of you, wait right there!
Zi Xia!
Geez, what the hell's going on?
（亜門）
ああ… 一体 どうなってんだ？
（江彰）知るか！
あのガキ！ 時間がねえってのに
The hell if I know!
That brat! We don't have time for this!
（紫夏）政さま！
（政）来るな！
Lord Zheng!
Stay away!
I... can't go to the State of Qin.
俺は 秦国へは帰れぬ
What are you talking about?
何を言って…
もう少しで帰れますよ
Just a little further and we'll be there.
（政）帰れぬ理由があるんだ
There's a reason I can't go!
What in the world?!
一体 何を… 気は確かですか？
Are you in your right mind?
There's no pain!
痛みがないんだ！
Not just pain. Taste, smells, heat and cold,  too.
痛みだけじゃない
味も 匂いも 暑さも 寒さも
I can't feel anything anymore.
俺は もう何も感じないんだ 何も…
Anything.
That can't be...
そんなバカな…
（政）フッ… そんなヤツが
王になどなれるわけがない
Nobody like that could ever become king.
Why in the world?
一体 どうして…
When I first gained awareness, I learned I was a member of the royal family.
物心ついたときは―
自分が王族だと知り
その幸運と名誉に心が震えた
My heart was shaken by that good fortune and honor.
But the moment I set foot outside, I was in the center of an enemy nation.
（政）だが １歩 外へ出ると
そこは敵国のど真ん中だった
The enemy nation that Qin killed 400,000 of in the battle of Changping.
秦国が 長平で40万人を
虐殺してしまった 正に その敵国の
Their hatred towards the State of Qin poured down upon me relentlessly.
秦国への憎悪が
容赦なく俺に降り注いだ
As I endured that overwhelming violence...
その圧倒的な暴力を受けながら
俺は 自分の置かれている状況を
認識し 絶望した
I became aware of the situation I had been left in... and despaired...
The days of oppression continued and my heart shut tight.
虐待の日々は続き
心は深く閉ざされ
いつしか俺は
何も感じなくなっていた
And at some point, I couldn't feel anything anymore...
How terrible.
（紫夏）なんてことだ
To be driven to something like this.
こんなことになるまで
追い詰められていたなんて
My god.
なんてことだ
Even though this boy is a prince of Qin, he was born in Zhao.
この子は秦国の王子でありながら
趙国で生まれた
Because of that horrible luck he could do nothing about...
どうすることも
できない その不運のせいで
he was forced to endure the malice of Changping.
長平の怨念を
受け止めさせられていたんだ
A boy of less than ten had no one reaching out their hand to him...
10に満たない子が―
誰にも手を差し伸べられず
たったひとりで ずっと…
He was always... all alone.
You can do it.
（紫夏）なれますよ
I'll show you, you can.
私が ならせてみせます
If you can't feel pain, then I'll feel it for you!
痛みがないのなら
私が代わりに感じてあげます
And tastes and smells. Everything...
味も 匂いも 全部…
But... it's okay.
（紫夏）でも 大丈夫
（泣き声）
You can definitely feel.
あなたは ちゃんと感じていますよ
That night, you were moved by the moonlight, weren't you?
あの晩 一緒に 月の輝きに
感動したじゃありませんか
It's okay. I'm with you.
（紫夏）大丈夫　私がついています
一緒に秦国へ帰りましょう
Now, let's bring you home to Qin together.
You've gotta be kidding me!
（商人）ふざけるな！
（商人）商談に間に合わねえよ！
I'm gonna miss a business deal!
（商人）聞いてねえぞ 閉門なんて
The closed gate isn't gonna listen to you!
（商人）責任者 出てこい！
（商人）あっ…
Whoever's in charge, get out here!
Three gold flags.
（商人）三黄旗(さんこうき)だ　王命の馬だ
（商人）なに？
Those are horses called by an imperial order.
What?!
Where's the one in charge here?!
（騎兵）
責任者 どこにおる？ 出てこい！
Get out here!
I'm the one in charge. What business do you have?
（役人Ｂ）私です　何事でしょうか
Did a merchant called Zi Xia come through here?!
（騎兵）紫夏という商人が
ここを通ったか？
Y-Yes. Half a day ago.
（役人Ｂ）は… はい 半日ほど前に
（騎兵）今すぐ門を開けろ！
Open the gate immediately!
It's a mounted unit.
（商人）騎馬隊だ
（商人）すげえ！
Awesome.
（商人）合戦でも始まんのか？
Is a battle starting?
That Zi Xia...
紫夏のヤツ 何かやらかしたのか？
Did she do something?
Come...
（紫夏）さあ
Lord Zheng!
政さま 大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
What's with this woman?
（幻影の声）何だ？ この女
政は帰らん　政は帰らん
Zheng won't go. He won't.
What's with this woman?
何だ？ この女　政は渡さん
政は俺たちが連れていく
I won't let you have Zheng.
Zheng is going with us.
To the abyss, with me...
俺たちと同じ地の底へ
Don't get in my way, woman.
（幻影の声）ジャマするな 女
お前も連れていくぞ
I'll bring you, too.
I'll bring the woman into the abyss, too.
女も地の底へ連れていく
Get away from me Zi Xia!
離れろ 紫夏！
俺に取りついてる亡霊たちが
お前にも…
The ghosts that are possessing me want you, too!
亡霊？
Ghosts?
It's really not going to work, Xia.
（政）やっぱりダメだ 紫夏
I... can't get away from these guys.
俺は こいつらからは逃げられない
Get a hold of yourself!
しっかりしろ！
亡霊なんて いやしない
全部 まやかしだ！
There are no ghosts!
They're all fake!
I'm the only one in front of you!
あなたの前には私しかいない！
全部 ただの幻だ！
Those are all just illusions!
It's warm...
（政）温かいな
Oh... It's the first time... I've felt this warmth...
そうか　初めてだ このぬくもりは
This is the first time... I've been hugged by someone like this.
誰かに
こうして抱きしめられるのは
初めてだ
Preview
Binding Wish
End